Heezen-Tharp collection: Arctic Ocean
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress
Heezen-Tharp collection: Arctic Ocean 1957-1995
G9781.C2 coll .H4 HT
Tharp, Marie
approximately 370 items
71 folders
2 boxes
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This sub-collection of the Heezen-Tharp maps and papers collection contains some 370 cartographic items and supporting materials that are related to Bruce Heezen and Marie Tharp's mapping of the Arctic Ocean floor. The item types include manuscript and published maps, soundings, reports, and other scientific data. The materials are stored offsite at Ft. Meade and must be requested advance of visiting the Geography and Map Reading Room.
Provenance
The materials were purchased by the Geography and Map Division throughout the 1990s.
Related Material
The parent collection is the Heezen-Tharp maps and papers collection.
Catalog Record: https://lccn.loc.gov/2017594025
Access and Restrictions
The Heezen-Tharp collection: Arctic Ocean collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Geography and Map Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
Consists of some 370 items related to Heezen and Tharp's mapping of the Arctic Ocean floor.
Arrangement
Important note: Each Group has a corresponding Holdings Number that can be located in Voyager by Library staff members. Item(s) filed within each Group have a corresponding Barcode number that Library staff members can locate in Voyager to retrieve it from Ft. Meade.
Some Groups or titles within Groups are labeled n/a. These items either were anticipated for acquisition in early processing stages or discarded at a later stage.
The Heezen-Tharp collection: World/Miscellaneous is organized in seven series:
Series I: Norwegian Sea: Group 01
Series II: Arctic Ocean: Groups 02 - 23
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Heezen, Bruce C.; Tharp, Marie, cartographer.
Subjects
Ocean bottom--Arctic Ocean--Maps.; Oceanography--Arctic Ocean--charts, diagrams, etc.; Submarine topography--Arctic Ocean--Maps.
Form/Genre
Bathymetric maps.; Manuscript maps.; Nautical charts.
Container List
- Series I: Norwegian Sea
  Group 01
  - Group 01 - Norwegian Tracks, 1759016
    4 items
    - a0001A Norwegian Sea and North, Tracks (Folder Barcode: 0027570569A)
      a. Film negative. b. 60˚ - 81˚ N to 60˚ W - 60˚ E. Notes: "Unknown cruise. Three-digit numbers must be station numbers. Two-digit numbers must be other stations. Unknown units."
    - a0001B Norwegian Sea and North, Tracks (Folder Barcode: 0027570569A)
    - a0002 (Folder Barcode: 0027570569A)
      a. Film positive. b. 60˚ - 81˚ N to 60˚ W - 60˚ E.
    - a0003 Norwegian Sea Floor - Lamont Profiler Tracks (Folder Barcode: 0027570569A)
      a. Film negative. b. 60˚ North to 81˚ North and 60˚ West to 60˚ East.
- Series II: Arctic Ocean
  Groups 02 - 23
  - Group 02 - Arctic Ocean Tracks, 17659031
    18 items
    - a0001 Eltanin 40 Tracks (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Paper. b. Computer plot of ship tracks between -20˚ to -45˚ and +170˚ to -155˚.
    - a0002 [VEMA Tracks] (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Film positive. Rolled item. b. 64˚ - 84˚ N to 75˚ W - 60˚ E. Includes track data from VEMA Cruises #23, 27, 28, 29.
    - a0003 [VEMA Tracks For Map #4] (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Film negative. b. Data for VEMA Cruises #21, 23, 27, 28.
    - a0004 [Seven Tracks with Numbers for the Arctic Mid-Ocean Ridge] (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Pencil sketch used in Nature Magazine, volume 215, #5102, page 724. Full polar projection. Notes: "1st and 2d profiles plotted backwards. 1st profile in wrong spot - #3, #4, 5, #6 OK. Don't use #7."
    - a0005 [Arctic Ocean Tracks Plot] (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Colored pencil plot.
    - a0006 [Tracks and Selected Soundings - Quadrant III] (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Notes: "Copy of Beal sub-soundings plotted by AGS. Has errors. See new corrected sheet. Jun 14, '74. Ed and John Beal's thesis."
    - a0007 Index to Lamont Profiler – Norwegian Sea and North Atlantic (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Paper. b. East.˚ West to 60˚ North and 60˚ to 81˚ From 60 Map 4.
    - a0008 Arctic Tracks (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Positive print. b. 20’˚ 30’ to 158˚ North and 154˚ 20’ to 73˚ From 72 West. Covers 1116 North
    - a0009 Index to Lamont Profiler (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Paper. b. West.˚ East to 45˚ North and 45˚ to 75˚ From 63 Color-coded, Map 4. 13 January 1976.
    - a0010 Index to Lamont Profiler Records (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. West.˚ East to 75˚ North and 60˚ to 84˚ From 63
    - a0011 Index to Lamont Profiler Records (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. East.˚ to 105˚ North and 50˚ to 84˚ From 63 Data for VEMA 23, Map 4.
    - a0012 Index to Lamont Profiler Records (Folder Barcode: 00275705706)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. East.˚ West to 60˚ North and 60˚ to 81˚ From 60 Includes Navy Index numbers and Matthews numbers.
    - b0001 [Arctic Soundings] Sheet 1A, 1:2,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Ozalid. b. Polar projection of hand plotted values taken from the GEBCO charts.
    - b0002 [Soundings, Feature Names and Elevations for Worksheet Item 0023] (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Ozalid.
    - b0003 Arctic Soundings (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Positive transparency.
    - b0004 Arctic Soundings (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Positive print. b. West.˚ to 157˚ North and 150˚ to 74˚ From 70 Off Point Barrow Alaska.
    - b0005 Arctic Soundings (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. West(?).˚ to 112˚ North and 106˚ to 10˚ From 5 Covers 2602 North.
    - b0006 Arctic (Folder Barcode: 00275705718)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. East.˚ to 20˚ North and 10˚ to 76˚ From 74 1030 – 3144 Soundings, 26 June 1974.
  - Group 03 - n/a, n/a
  - Group 04 - Arctic Ocean Selected Soundings, 17660893
    7 items
    - c0001 [Arctic Ocean Basin Selected Soundings, 1975 - Quadrant I] (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Sheet 1. Pencil plot of data from Russian maps at scales of 1:2,500,000 and 1:250,000. AGS.
    - c0002 [Selected Soundings for Arctic Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pen and colored pencil plots. Note: "Errors on this sheet - 6/12/74."
    - c0003 [Selected Soundings of Norway Quadrant II] (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Notes: "Beal thesis. Compilation by AGS. Marked incorrect."
    - c0004 [Arctic Soundings] (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Ozalid. b. Note: "This sheet is a paper Ozalid of the negative. It looks like the original was part of a Russian chart. It appears to me that the soundings that are not in parenthesis are soundings that are fathoms written over the printed depths in meters. Written by Oscar Bradley Eckoff, 8 February 1972." Printed on British Admiralty Chart 2116N.
    - c0005 [USS Burton Island Selected Soundings] (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. 69˚ 30' and 90˚ to 91˚ West. Tracks and selected soundings around Peter I Island.
    - c0006 Source Material Overlay 1003 North (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
      a. Positive print. b. West.˚ to 100˚ North and 90˚ to 17˚ From 10 Covers 1003 North.
    - c0007 Source Material Overlay 1003 North (Folder Barcode: 0027570572A)
  - Group 05 - Arctic Ocean Precision Depth Recordings and Profiles, 17660900
    9 items
    - d0001 [Collection of Arctic Profiles] (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil diagram with depths and coordinate locations.
    - d0002 Arctic Profiles (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Linen. b. Covers Grand Banks and Chukchi Shelf.
    - d0003 Arctic Profiles (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      c. Linen. d. Covers Marvin Ridge, Lomonosov Ridge, and Walvis Ridge.
    - d0004 Arctic Ocean and Norwegian Sea Profiles (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Positive print. b. Five profiles, taken in 1948.
    - d0005 Arctic Ocean and Norwegian Sea Profiles (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Linen. b. Five profiles, taken in 1948. Original inked graphic.
    - d0006 Transatlantic Profiles across (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Negative print, composite. b. Profiles, A-A’, B-B’, C-C’
    - d0007 Bathymetric Profile of the (?) Rise (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Positive print. b. 29’ to ˚ 53’ North and 160˚ 30’ to 77˚ From 77 33’ West.˚ 173
    - d0008 Bathymetric Profile across the Arctic Basin (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Negative print. b. Based on soundings from the SSN Nautilus. Figure 1.
    - d0009 Bathymetric Profile across the Arctic Basin (Folder Barcode: 00275705731)
      a. Positive print. b. Based on soundings from the SSN Nautilus. Figure 1.
  - Group 06 - Arctic Ocean Cores, 17660908
    - e0001 World Core Map - 12/1 (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid. b. Base map. 63˚ to 84˚ North and 95˚ West to 165˚ East. Does not contain any plotted data.
    - e0002 World Core Map - 12/2 (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid. b. VEMA Data plotted in vicinity of Greenland, 63˚ to 84˚ North and 5˚ East to 95˚ West.
    - e0003 World Core Map - 12/3 (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid. b. VEMA data plotted in the vicinity of Novaya Zemlya. 63˚ to 84˚ North and 5˚ to 105˚ East.
    - e0004 Kara Sea, Barents Sea, and Arctic Sea Cores (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid. b. VEMA cruises #23, #27, #28, and #30. Pencil annotations indicate core materials. 63˚ to 84˚ North and 5˚ to 105˚ East.
    - e0005 Lamont Cores in the Norwegian Sea (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Positive transparency. b. ˚ West to 60˚ North and 30˚ to 90˚ From 74 East.
    - e0006 Lamont Piston Cores in the North Eurasian Sea (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. ˚ to 165˚ North and 65˚ to 84˚ From 65 East.
    - e0007 Lamont Piston Cores Arctic Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. ˚ to 165˚ North and 105˚ to 84˚ From 63 West.
    - e0008 Lamont Piston Cores off Greenland (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. ˚ to 90˚ North and 0˚ to 84˚ From 63 West. Date from VEMA 23, 27-30.
    - e0009 Lamont Piston Cores Arctic Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275705743)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. ˚ to 105˚ North and 15˚ to 84˚ From 63 East. Date from VEMA 23, 27, 28, 30.
  - Group 07 - Arctic Ocean Geology (Rocks and Sediments), 17660913
    5 items
    - f0001 [Worksheet of Arctic Contours from Russian Map]
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil. Quadrant I.
    - f0002 Tectonic and Volcanic Activity of the Arctic Regions (Last one million years) (Folder Barcode: 00275706164)
      a. Paper. b. Compiled by Paul D. Lowman Jr, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center, 1980
    - f0003 [French Geologic Map of the Arctic] (Folder Barcode: 00275706164)
      a. Paper. b. Color computer print. Polar projection.
    - f0004 Arctic Fracture Zones, Province Names, and Tectonics (Folder Barcode: 00275706164)
      a. Frosted Acetate. b. to˚ East and West, and 90˚ to 180˚ From 0 North.˚ 90
    - f0005 Sediment Chart (Folder Barcode: 00275706164)
      a. Graph paper. b. Lithology of deep sea sediments.
  - Group 08 - Arctic Ocean Earthquakes and Seismicity, 17660919
    13 items
    - g0001 Seismicity of the Arctic and Adjoining Regions 1960-1983) Reston, VA: U.S. Geological Survey, Open-file Report 84-376, A.F. Espinosa and J.A. Michael, 1984. (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Ozalid. b. Lambert equal area projection. Twelve inset maps showing magnitude and hypo central locations or depth-of-focus in kilometers.
    - g0002 Seismicity of Alaska and Aleutian Islands (1960-1983) Reston, VA: U.S. Geological Survey, Open-file Report 84-855, A.F. Espinosa, 1984, 1:12,500,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Ozalid. b. Modified - stereographic conformal projection. Eleven inset maps showing magnitude and hypo central location or depth-of-focus in kilometers.
    - g0003 Seismicity of the Arctic ESSA, 1961 - Sept. 1969. (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Paper. b. Polar projection. Coast and Geodetic Center epicenters plotted.
    - g0004 [Plot of Seismic Activity for Quadrant I, Arctic Ocean Basin, 1975] (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil and ink plot of probable epicenters. Note: "Look for others on shelf"
    - g0005 Arctic Seismicity (1908-1975) (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Film negative. b. EPB Publication, Vol. 45, No. 4, Plate 2, 1:7,500,000
    - g0006A-E Seismicity Along the Artic Ridge (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Ozalid and graph paper. b. Four profiles covering the Barents Shelf, Boyd Bank, and off Spitsbergen.
    - g0007 Russian Map of the Arctic (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Negative print. b. North.˚ to 90˚ East/West and 90˚ to 180˚ From 0 Polar projection. Shows earthquake locations and magnitudes.
    - g0008 Arctic Earthquakes (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Negative print. b. Polar projection. Shows earthquake locations and magnitudes. Final publication graphic.
    - g0009 Polar Projection graphic for g0008 (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Negative print. b. Polar projection.
    - g0010 Polar Projection graphic for g0008 (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Positive print. b. Polar projection.
    - g0011 Arctic Earthquake Locations (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Ozalid paper. b. Polar projection. Shows earthquake locations and magnitudes – mostly for USSR.
    - g0012 Arctic Earthquake Locations (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
    - g0013 Arctic Earthquake Locations (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
  - Group 09 - Arctic Ocean Magnetics, 17660924
    1 items
    - 0001 Ancient Pole Positions (Folder Barcode: 00275706176)
      a. Negative print. b. North polar projection. Includes N. American, Indian, and European data.
  - Group 10 - Arctic Ocean German Water Data, 17660928
    3 items
    - k0001 German Water data (Folder Barcode: 0027570619A)
      c. Positive print. d. West.˚ to 18˚ North and 0˚ to 65˚ From 61
    - k0002 German Water data (Folder Barcode: 0027570619A)
      a. Negative print. b. West.˚ to 40˚ North and 20˚ to 68˚ From 64
    - k0003 Radiocarbon Sea Water Sample Ages (Folder Barcode: 0027570619A)
      a. Negative print. b. Shows percent difference from modern wood.
  - Group 11 - Arctic Ocean Indexes, 17660933
    - l0001 [Index Map for Quadrant I Coverage] (Folder Barcode: 00275706206)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil drawing of contours and blue pencil plot of map coverage. Descriptive index for eight U.S. and U.S.S.R. maps.
    - l0002 [Index Map for Quadrant II Coverage] (Folder Barcode: 00275706206)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Ink drawing of contours and blue pencil plot of map coverage. Descriptive index for twelve U.S. and U.S.S.R. maps.
    - l0003 [Index Map for Quadrant III Coverage] (Folder Barcode: 00275706206)
      a. Tracing paper b. Pencil and ink contours
    - l0004 [Index Map for Quadrant IV Coverage] (Folder Barcode: 00275706206)
      a. Tracing paper b. Pen and ink contours
    - l0005 Arctic Index (Folder Barcode: 00275706206)
      a. Tracing paper b. ˚ to 360˚ North and 0˚ to 60˚ From 52 Key to map extension land only.
  - Group 12 - Arctic Ocean U.S. Navy Index, 17660940
    43 items
    - 0114N (Folder Barcode: 00275706218)
      0001 Color coded track map. 0002 Color coded soundings. 0003 Soundings map. 0004 Plotting sheet. 20 July 1964.
    - 0115N (Folder Barcode: 0027570622A)
      0001 Color-coded soundings. 0002 Color-coded soundings. 0003 Color-coded soundings. 0004 Color-coded soundings.
    - 0115N - 2415N (Folder Barcode: 00275706231)
      0001 Norway Abyssal Plain andParts of Dumshaf Abyssal Plain a. Frosted acetate. b. Notes: "64˚ to 69˚ North and 9˚ West to 6˚ East. February 12, 1976." 0002 Tracks and contours (1 of 2). 0003 Province map. 0004 Matthews areas.
    - 0116N (Folder Barcode: 00275706243)
      0001 Color-coded tracks. 0002 Soundings. 0003 Soundings and select soundings. 0004 Color-coded soundings. 0005 Color-coded soundings. 0006 Color-coded soundings.
    - 0116N and2416N-1 (Folder Barcode: 00275706255)
      0001 Tracks on Provinces a. Frosted acetate. b. Colored shading. Note: "Jan Mayer to Fz Ridge." 0002 Preliminary Contours a. Tracing paper. b. Includes tracks and earthquake plots. 0003 Tracks on Provinces a. Tracing paper. b. Preliminary province worksheet including tracks. 0004 Earthquake Tracks a. Tracing paper. b. Colored pencil plot of earthquakes and tracks. Includes selected soundings.
    - 0117N (Folder Barcode: 00275706255)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Soundings. 0003 Color-coded soundings. 0004 Color-coded soundings. 0005 Color-coded soundings. 0006 Color-coded soundings.
    - 0117N - 0118N (Folder Barcode: 00275706255)
      0001 Tracks. 0002 Soundings. 0003 Soundings. 0004 Soundings. 0005 Soundings.
    - 0118N (Folder Barcode: 00275706255)
      0001 Color-coded track. 0002 Soundings.
    - 0119N (Folder Barcode: 00275706292)
      0001 Color-coded track.
    - 0214N (Folder Barcode: 00275706292)
      0001 Tracks. 0002 Soundings. 0003 Color-coded tracks. 0004 Soundings. 0005 Soundings. 0006 Color-coded select soundings. 0007 Color-coded select soundings. 0008 Color-coded select soundings.
    - 0215N (Folder Barcode: 00275706292)
      0001 Color-coded soundings. 0002 Color-coded soundings. 0003 Color-coded soundings. 0004 Color-coded soundings. 0005 Color-coded soundings. 0006 Soundings. 0007 Soundings.
    - 0216N (Folder Barcode: 00275706322)
      0001 Tracks. 0002 Tracks (British) 0003 Select soundings. 0004 Color-coded soundings. 0005 Color-coded soundings. 0006 Color-coded soundings.
    - 0216N – 0116N, 0215N – 0115N (Folder Barcode: 00275706334)
      0001 Earthquakes and tracks on Matthew’s areas. 0002 Soundings. 0003 Tracks and province map.
    - 0314N (Folder Barcode: 00275706346)
      0001 Tracks. 0002 Color-coded tracks. 0003 Color-coded tracks. Classification notice. 0004 Tracks. Collection sheet 10 November 1977. 0005 Tracks. 0006 Select soundings. Classification notice. 0007 Color-coded tracks. Collection sheet 3 Aug. 1973. 0008 Color-coded select-soundings. 0009 Earthquakes. Classification notice.
    - 0314N – 0215N (Folder Barcode: 00275706358)
      0001 Contours.
    - 0315N (Folder Barcode: 0027570636A)
      0001 Color-coded select soundings. 0002 Tracks. 0003 Tracks and Soundings.
    - 0414N (Folder Barcode: 00275706371)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Color-coded soundings. 3 August 1973. 0003 Soundings. 0004 Soundings. December 1977.
    - 0415N (Folder Barcode: 00275706383)
      0001 Soundings. 3 August 1973.
    - 0416N (Folder Barcode: 00275706395)
      0001 Color-coded track. 0002 Select soundings. 3 August 1973.
    - 0513N (Folder Barcode: 00275706395)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Soundings (corrections to 0001). 0003 Color-coded soundings. Collected 11 January 1956. 0004 Color-coded soundings. Collected 11 January 1956.
    - 0513N – 0613N (Folder Barcode: 00275706413)
      0001 Color-coded tracks. Erika Dan 4
    - 0514N (Folder Barcode: 00275706425)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Color-coded soundings.
    - 0516N (Folder Barcode: 00275706437)
      0001 Color-coded select soundings, 3 Aug 1973. 0002 Soundings. Erika Dan 4. 0003 Color-coded select soundings.
    - 0614N (Folder Barcode: 00275706449)
      0001 Select Soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0002 Color-coded soundings. 0003 Select soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0004 Select soundings. Classification notation. 0005 Color-coded tracks. 3 Aug. 1973.
    - 0714N (Folder Barcode: 00275706450)
      0001 Select Soundings. June 1961.
    - 1116N (Folder Barcode: 00275706462)
      0001 Select Soundings. 0002 Select Soundings. 0003 Select Soundings.
    - 1215N (Folder Barcode: 00275706474)
      0001 Tracks.
    - 1714N (Folder Barcode: 00275706498)
      0001 Select soundings. April 1961. 0002 Select soundings.
    - 1814N (Folder Barcode: 00275706504)
      0001 Soundings. June 1959. 0002 Soundings.
    - 1914N (Folder Barcode: 00275706516)
      0001 Select soundings.
    - 2215N (Folder Barcode: 00275706528)
      0001 Soundings.
    - 2216N (Folder Barcode: 0027570653A)
    - 2217N (Folder Barcode: 00275706541)
    - 2315N (Folder Barcode: 00275706553)
    - 2316N (Folder Barcode: 00275706565)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Soundings with corrections.
    - 2317N (Folder Barcode: 00275706577)
    - 2317N – 2318N, 2417N – 2418N (Folder Barcode: 00275706589)
      0001 Tracks. 0002 Tracks. 0003 Tracks.
    - 2415N (Folder Barcode: 00275706590, 00275706607)
      0001 Track. 0002 Track. 0003 Track. 0004 Color-coded tracks. May 1963 andFeb. 1964. 0005 Color-coded soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0006 Color-coded tracks. 26 June 1973. 0007 Color-coded tracks and soundings. 0008 Color-coded tracks. 0009 Color-coded tracks. 0010 Color-coded tracks and soundings. 3 Aug. 1973 0011 Soundings. May 1963. 0012 Soundings. May 1963.
    - 2416N (Folder Barcode: 00275706619)
      0001 Color-coded soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0002 Color-coded tracks. 0003 Tracks. 0004 Color-coded soundings. 0005 Soundings. 0006 Soundings and contours. 0007 Color-coded tracks. 0008 Computer-plotted soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0009 Soundings. March 1964. 0010 Tracks for the IGY. 0011 Tracks. 21 April 1964.
    - 2417N (Folder Barcode: 00275706620)
      0001 Color-coded tracks. 3 Aug. 1973. 0002 Color-coded tracks. 0003 Color-coded soundings and contours. 0004 Soundings. 0005 Tracks. 0006 Color-coded tracks and soundings. 3 Aug. 1973. 0007 Select soundings.
    - 2417N - 2418N (Folder Barcode: 00275706632)
      0001 Soundings. 0002 Tracks. 26 June 1974. 0003 Soundings. 26 June 1974. 0004 Tracks. 26 June 1974. 0005 Select soundings. 0006 Tracks and Soundings.
    - 2418N (Folder Barcode: 00275706644, 00275706656)
      0001 Select soundings. 0002 Color-coded soundings. Computer plotted, on frosted acetate. 0003 Select soundings. 0004 Soundings. 0005 Tracks. 0006 Soundings. 0007 Contours and Soundings. 26 June 1974. 0008 Tracks.
    - 3614N (Folder Barcode: 00275706668)
      0001 Color-coded soundings. 0002 Color-coded tracks. 0003 Color-coded soundings.
  - Group 13 - Arctic Ocean Bathymetry, 17659028
    - 0001 [Arctic Bathymetry] (Folder Barcode: 0027570667A)
      a. Film positive. b. Polar projection.
    - 0002 Arctic Revised Bathymetry (Folder Barcode: 0027570667A)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Polar projection.
    - 0003 Bathymetric Map of the Central Arctic Basin (Folder Barcode: 0027570667A)
      a. Positive print. b. Polar projection. Figure 13, 1954.
  - Group 14 - Arctic Ocean Contours, 17660518
    20 items
    - b0001 [Arctic Contours] Sheet 2, 1:2,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Ozalid. b. From American Geographical Society, 1975. Polar stereographic. Depths in meters.
    - b0002 [Contours for Portion of the Arctic, 1966 - 1969] Based on Sheet 3, GEBCO Chart, 1:2,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Ozalid. b. One centimeter equals 20 km.
    - b0003 [Arctic Province Map] Sheet 4, 1960?, 1:2,000,000. (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Ozalid. b. "For Miss M. Tharp."
    - b0004 [Contour Map of Polar Region] (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)
      a. Ozalid. b. Un-annotated base map covering Alaskan coast showing drainage and contours on the land and bathymetry.
    - b0005 Contour Map of Polar Region Washington, DC: National Geographic Society. (Folder Barcode: 00275706681)